<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.9.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2020-08-31T01:07:02-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">rlee360</title><subtitle>An amazing website.</subtitle><author><name>Richard Lee</name><email>Lee66@cooper.edu</email></author><entry><title type="html">Hello, World!</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/musings/helloworld/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Hello, World!" /><published>1969-12-31T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>1969-12-31T06:59:59-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/musings/helloworld</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/musings/helloworld/">&lt;h1 id=&quot;first&quot;&gt;First&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As someone whose first introduction to programming was a Hello World script on a &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/BASIC_Stamp&quot;&gt;BASIC Stamp&lt;/a&gt; circa 2009, I always feel the urge to write some form of Hello World on every new platform or language I pick up, almost as a good luck ritual. Something about knowing that my program can greet me makes me feel a little better – almost as if I have the grace of the gods to proceed on my perilous journey.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As to the phrase “Hello, World!” itself: in its original form, the clause was all lowercase, no exclamation point, with the two words separated by a single comma and space. The importance of this comma is &lt;a href=&quot;https://english.stackexchange.com/questions/74985/should-the-beginners-program-read-hello-world&quot;&gt;sometimes contested&lt;/a&gt;, and these days many programmers opt to exclude it. The use of the phrase “Hello, World!” was popularized by the widely renowned book &lt;em&gt;The C Programming Language&lt;/em&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The only way to learn a new programming language is by writing programs in it. The first program to write is the same for all languages:&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Print the words&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;hello, world&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;This is a big hurdle; to leap over it you have to be able to create the program text somewhere, compile it successfully, load it, run it, and find out where your output went. &lt;strong&gt;With these mechanical details mastered, everything else is comparatively easy.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p class=&quot;small&quot;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Kernighan and Ritchie, The C Programming Language&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;second&quot;&gt;Second&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m not quite sure how accurate that last statement is. I don’t exactly consider the book light reading for someone who has never coded before. However, after learning C once and then coming back to this book, I can see why it is &lt;strong&gt;the&lt;/strong&gt; reference on C.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As for the sub-title text, that’s a humorous reference to the &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Unix_time&quot;&gt;Unix Epoch time&lt;/a&gt;, which is essentially when time began for Unix computers. Unix Epoch time is recorded as seconds since 12:00 AM January 1&lt;sup&gt;st&lt;/sup&gt;, 1970. Since that time is in UTC, the equivalent time in the US would be December 31&lt;sup&gt;st&lt;/sup&gt;, 1969 7:00 PM, which, if a programmer &lt;a href=&quot;https://stackoverflow.com/questions/34891782/what-could-cause-a-mysql-time-stamp-to-equal-december-31-1969&quot;&gt;misinterprets time strings&lt;/a&gt;, will likely cause this date to rear its end. Epic problems caused by Epoch problems.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Richard Lee</name><email>Lee66@cooper.edu</email></author><summary type="html">Tackling the origins of Hello World from before the beginning of time.</summary></entry></feed>